<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Huzaif</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/huz4f/huz4f.git/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Huzaif</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/huz4f/huz4f.git/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>📚 Completed</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/huz4f/huz4f.git/blogs/books/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/huz4f/huz4f.git/blogs/books/</guid>
      <description>List of books i&amp;rsquo;ve read and courses i&amp;rsquo;ve went through:
Data Structure &amp;amp; Algorithms
Grokking Algorithms -Aditya Bhargava </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Technological Ramifications</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/huz4f/huz4f.git/blogs/tech/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/huz4f/huz4f.git/blogs/tech/</guid>
      <description>We all know technological advancements have been drastically changing human lives, from extending our lifespan to ease of many tasks we now take for granted.
Technology is so intertwined with our lives right now that it&amp;rsquo;s hard to imagine life without modern conveniences. So what are these Ramifications of Technology and how has it affected our lives beyond its marvellous breakthroughs?
Dividing this into 3 parts Psychological effects Physical changes Social Adaptation Also wrote about Exposure of kids to youtube / social media at a very young age</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shepherd, Sheep and Legs</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/huz4f/huz4f.git/blogs/sheep/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/huz4f/huz4f.git/blogs/sheep/</guid>
      <description>Came across this while reading a book:
Story is about a little sheep in a Shepherd&amp;rsquo;s flock,
This little sheep liked to wander off and Mr.Shepherd after noticing it couple times broke off all his legs (brutal right). Aren&amp;rsquo;t shephered supposed to love sheep?
Now he holds this 4 legged broken sheep everywhere around his neck, feeding, washing and taking care of everything and when finally the sheep is ready to go.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blockchain &amp; Smart Contracts</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/huz4f/huz4f.git/projects/blockchain/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/huz4f/huz4f.git/projects/blockchain/</guid>
      <description>Blocks and Hashing Smart Contract Blockchain: -&amp;gt; Have written about Blockchain in Articles.
Demonstration: How BlockChain works using cocoa and SHA-1 checksum utility
-&amp;gt; One block connected to the genesis block and hash function with 2 zeroes at start Have also uploaded this swift code on GitHub: Here ( needs shasum file for the hash )
Understanding Code: Block in a blockchain consists of Block Header &amp;amp; Body
The head consists of:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/huz4f/huz4f.git/articles/blockchain/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/huz4f/huz4f.git/articles/blockchain/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Data is everywhere and everything in today&amp;rsquo;s day and age&amp;rsquo; Advancement in technology has enabled us to keep our data online from our private credentials to backup of our gallery photos. You don&amp;rsquo;t need local storage and access.
But there is no cloud is there?
Just some server on the internet that contains our precious data, that can be used in devastating ways against us from knowing our personal info to having our every digital footprint recorded.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/huz4f/huz4f.git/articles/web--browsers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/huz4f/huz4f.git/articles/web--browsers/</guid>
      <description>Ever questioned how do you see a website? visiting my website through a Browser?
The browser goes to the DNS server and finds the real address of the server that the website lives on (IP address). Browser sends an HTTP request to the server, asking it to send a copy of the website you asked for. This message and all other data sent between the client and the server, is sent across your internet connection using TCP/IP.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/huz4f/huz4f.git/articles/clouds--ml/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/huz4f/huz4f.git/articles/clouds--ml/</guid>
      <description>Cloud Computing &amp;amp; Modern day ML From being able to run tensorflow on collab to training models on sagemaker, By using cloud, complicated tasks of installing and managing dependencies on your local computer are taken care of. Not to mention worring about the limiting factors of your hardware. Cloud computing makes practice of ML accessible to everyone and implementation readily availabe.
Evolvement and need of Machine Learning: We know, Machine Learning has evolved tremendously over the past decade and now has applications in nearly every field.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About me?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/huz4f/huz4f.git/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/huz4f/huz4f.git/about/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;it just looks cool&amp;rsquo; , i won&amp;rsquo;t write about myself go read articles</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
