<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Huzaif</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/huz4f/huz4f.git/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Huzaif</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/huz4f/huz4f.git/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Paradox Human Freedom</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/huz4f/huz4f.git/blogs/choice/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/huz4f/huz4f.git/blogs/choice/</guid>
      <description>Choices Create illusion, No Liberation. “We search for purpose. The universe offers silence.” -The Myth of Sisyphus
Every goal you achieve, every milestone you hit, every desire that once burned within you — when finally attained, somehow loses its power.
Choice is not about “right or wrong” — it’s about choosing to live with full consciousness, despite the absurd.
It fades. The shine dulls. And you&amp;rsquo;re left wondering: Was that it?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Technological Ramifications</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/huz4f/huz4f.git/blogs/tech/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/huz4f/huz4f.git/blogs/tech/</guid>
      <description>We all know technological advancements have drastically changed human lives, from extending our lifespan to ease of many tasks that now we take for granted.
Technology is so intertwined with our lives right now that it&amp;rsquo;s hard to imagine life without modern conveniences. So what are these Ramifications of Technology? How has it affected our lives beyond its marvellous breakthroughs?
Dividing this into 3 parts, Psychological effects Physical changes Social Adaptation Psychological Let&amp;rsquo;s start with the obvious one,</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shepherd, Sheep and Legs</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/huz4f/huz4f.git/blogs/sheep/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/huz4f/huz4f.git/blogs/sheep/</guid>
      <description>Came across this while reading a book:
Story is about a little sheep in a Shepherd&amp;rsquo;s flock.
This little sheep liked to wander off and Shepherd after noticing it couple of times broke off all it&amp;rsquo;s legs (brutal right). Aren&amp;rsquo;t shephered supposed to love sheep?
Now he carries this 4 legged broken sheep everywhere around his neck, feeding, washing and taking care of everything till finally the sheep is ready to go.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blockchain &amp; Smart Contracts</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/huz4f/huz4f.git/projects/blockchain/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/huz4f/huz4f.git/projects/blockchain/</guid>
      <description>Blocks and Hashing Smart Contract Blockchain: -&amp;gt; Have also written: Blockchain.
Demonstration: How BlockChain works using cocoa and SHA-1 checksum utility
-&amp;gt; One block connected to the genesis block and hash function with 2 zeroes at start Swiftcode on GitHub: Here ( needs shasum file for the hash )
Understanding Code: Block in a blockchain consists of Block Header &amp;amp; Body
The head consists of:
Previous block&amp;rsquo;s hash Merkel root (compact hash sum of all transactions) Block version Nonce (it is calculated) Timestamp The condition you set for which nonce is calculated The body consists of Transaction lists.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/huz4f/huz4f.git/articles/blockchain/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/huz4f/huz4f.git/articles/blockchain/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Data is everywhere and everything in today&amp;rsquo;s day and age&amp;rsquo; Advancement in technology has enabled us to keep our data online from our private credentials to backup of our gallery photos. You don&amp;rsquo;t need local storage and access.
But there is no cloud is there?
Just some server on the internet that contains our precious data, that can be used in devastating ways against us from knowing our personal info to having our every digital footprint recorded.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/huz4f/huz4f.git/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/huz4f/huz4f.git/about/</guid>
      <description>i like norepinephrine</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
